There are hundreds of personality quizzes online that assert they can ascertain whether the right or left half of your brain is dominant.
网上有数以百计的性格小测试，声称能够确定你的大脑是右半边还是左半边占主导。
Left-brained people are supposedly logical and excel at language and math while right-brained people are more imaginative, emotionally intelligent and skilled with spatial reasoning.
据说，左脑型的人逻辑性强，擅长语言和数学；而右脑型的人则更富有想象力、情商更高，也更善于空间推理。
There’s just one problem: That’s not how brains work.
问题只有一个：大脑并不是这样运作的。
Popular science enthusiasts sort of took this idea and ran with it, and it’s become woven in popular culture now, and it’s not going away.
科普爱好者们可以说是接过了这一观点并大加发挥，如今它已经融入了大众文化，而且不会消失。
Despite this enduring belief, there’s no such thing as being “right-brained” or “left-brained”.
尽管这种观念经久不衰，但并没有“右脑型”或“左脑型”这回事。
Whether you’re someone who tends more towards creativity or logic has nothing to do with one hemisphere of your brain being dominant over the other.
你是更偏向创造力还是更偏向逻辑，与你大脑的一个半球比另一个半球占优势毫无关系。
But the actual science of how the two halves of our brains work together is sometimes stranger than fiction.
但我们大脑的两半如何协同工作，其科学真相有时比小说还要离奇。
The human brain is divided into two hemispheres, the left and right.
人脑分为两个半球：左半球和右半球。
In all vertebrate animals, the right hemisphere controls the left side of the body and vice versa.
在所有脊椎动物中，右半球控制身体的左侧，反之亦然。
And scientists have long known, thanks to the behaviors of patients who suffered brain injuries, that different areas of the brain do different things.
而且，科学家们早就通过脑损伤患者的行为表现得知，大脑的不同区域负责不同的事情。
But many scientists struggled with this idea, because the very suggestion that the left and right halves of the brain operate differently disrupted the idea that nature tends toward perfect symmetry.
但许多科学家很难接受这一观点，因为单是提出大脑左右两半的运作方式不同，就打破了自然界趋向于完美对称的观念。
Work by neuroscientists has revealed the importance of different hemispheres of the brain for different activities.
神经科学家的研究揭示了大脑不同半球对不同活动的重要性。
However, their research quickly saw some misinterpretations in the general public: Some presumed creative people must be right-brained and logical people left-brained.
然而，他们的研究很快就在普通大众中遭到了一些误读：有些人想当然地认为，有创造力的人一定是右脑型，而逻辑性强的人一定是左脑型。
It is proven that not only is personality unrelated to the different halves of the brain, but people aren’t really right- or left-brained to begin with.
事实证明，不仅性格与大脑的左右两半无关，而且人其实本来就没有右脑型和左脑型之分。
The idea that we have left-dominant people and right-dominant people, and that this is related to personality, is categorically false.
认为人有左脑主导型和右脑主导型之分，并且这与性格有关，这种观点是绝对错误的。
That’s never been supported in the neuroscience community.
这一观点从未得到神经科学界的支持。
Neuroscientists don’t believe that and never have.
神经科学家并不相信这一点，也从来没有相信过。
What scientists learned is that there are really important differences between the left hemisphere and the right hemisphere.
科学家们认识到的是，左半球和右半球之间存在着非常重要的差异。
It’s just that they have nothing to do with personality or whether one’s cognitive strategy is more logical or free-spirited or creative.
只不过，这些差异既与性格毫无关系，也与一个人的认知策略是更讲逻辑、更自由奔放还是更有创造力毫无关系。
While researchers have shown the limitations of how the hemispheres of our brains influence our lives, it’s not difficult to understand the appeal of such ideas.
虽然研究人员已经表明，大脑半球对我们生活的影响是有限的，但这类观点的吸引力并不难理解。
People are endlessly fascinated by themselves and their friends, and the subtle differences in how people think about the world are really meaningful to them.
人们对自己和朋友总是着迷不已，而人与人在看待世界的方式上存在的细微差异，对他们来说真的很有意义。
When you come up with an online quiz that tells us something about ourselves, we’re drawn to that.
一旦你想出一个在线小测试，能告诉我们自己的一些情况，我们就会被它吸引。
It’s irresistible.
这让人无法抗拒。
But you have to take it with an enormous grain of salt.
但你必须对它保持高度怀疑。